{"id":"2017_23","name":"Romans Lesson 232017_23","memoryVerse":"“So in Christ we, though many, form one body, and each member belongs to all the others.” – Romans 12:5","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2017_23_1","questionText":"1. What was meaningful to you in the lecture?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_23_2","questionText":"2. What help did you receive from the notes?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Romans 12:9-13.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"12:9-13"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_23_3","questionText":"3. What does Paul want you to keep in mind as you read these verses? How might remembering help you obey these commands? (See Romans 12:1-2.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"12:1-2"}]},{"id":"2017_23_4","questionText":"4. Compare Paul’s description of love with the popular view of love in your culture. How does hating what is evil relate to sincere love?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_23_5","questionText":"5. Compare the Bible’s description of evil with the popular view of evil in your culture.  Proverbs 8:13","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"8:13"}]},{"id":"2017_23_5b","questionText":"5.  Proverbs 13:5","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Proverbs","verse":"13:5"}]},{"id":"2017_23_5c","questionText":"5.  Ecclesiastes 3:8","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Ecclesiastes","verse":"3:8"}]},{"id":"2017_23_5d","questionText":"5.  Isaiah 61:8","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Isaiah","verse":"61:8"}]},{"id":"2017_23_5e","questionText":"5.  Amos 5:15","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Amos","verse":"5:15"}]},{"id":"2017_23_5f","questionText":"5.  Luke 14:26","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Luke","verse":"14:26"}]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Romans 12:9-13.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"12:9-13"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_23_6","questionText":"6. Which individuals or groups is it hard for you to honor above yourself? Why?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_23_7","questionText":"7. Put verse 11 in your own words. How is it relevant to your current circumstances?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_23_8","questionText":"8. Which of Paul’s commands in Romans 12:9-13 is hardest for you to obey? Why?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"12:9-13"}]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Romans 12:14-16.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"12:14-16"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_23_9","questionText":"  9. How does a person bless persecutors? Whom might you come alongside and bless? (See Matthew 5:44; Luke 6:27-28 or any other Scriptures.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Matthew","verse":"5:44"},{"book":"Luke","verse":"6:27-28"}]},{"id":"2017_23_10","questionText":"10. What strategies for healthy relationships are found in these verses? What opportunities is God giving you to practice these commands?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_23_11","questionText":"11. How does pride destroy relationships? Share an example of how humility has mended or restored relationships.","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_23_12","questionText":"12. How have you been helped by someone who has come alongside you to weep, grieve or mourn with you?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Romans 12:17-21.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"12:17-21"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_23_13","questionText":"13. Share ways people repay evil for evil today. Which ones are tempting to you?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_23_14","questionText":"14. Give examples from Scripture of those who did not repay evil for evil. What were the results?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_23_15","questionText":"15. What is the believer’s responsibility to their enemies? What does Scripture promise God will do?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_23_16","questionText":"16. How can a person live the kind of life Paul is commanding in Romans 12:9-21?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"12:9-21"}]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Romans 12:9-21.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"12:9-21"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_23_17","questionText":"17. What have you learned about God in this week’s study? How may your group pray for you as you make this truth a part of your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_23_18","questionText":"18. Homiletics for group and administrative leaders: Romans 12:9-21","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"12:9-21"}]}]}}}